A Guide to the Withers Papers (Chitwood Collection), 1881-1943, Undated.
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
- Series II. Examiner of Records to the Auditor of Public Accounts - Correspondence. 1900-1907, 30 folders.
  - Folder 5. Correspondence - Carroll County. 16 April 1907 - 19 April 1907, 7 items. (Series-folder 2:5)
    This folder contains letters re: Eliza J. Austin, guardian, Austinville; A. N. Matthews, Guardian of Carl C. Cooley, Gap; H. L. Puckett, administrator of the estate of S. W. Tompkins, Cana; Stephen Wilkerson, administrator of the estate of W. C. Smith, Hillsville; William Foster, commissioner in the chancery cause of J. W. Beasley vs. A. D. Robinson et als, Hillsville; W. J. Jackson and E. B. Jackson, administrators of the estate of John Jackson, Laurel Fork; and S. W. Tompkins, administrator of the estate of F. M. Puckett, Hillsville.
  - Folder 6. Correspondence - Carroll County. 12 April 1907 - 15 April 1907., 7 items. (Series-folder 2:6)
    This folder contains letters re: Mrs. E. J. Austin, guardian, Cap; B. F. Fulks, guardian of Posey Vernon and Willie Vernon, Lambsburg; C. W. Utt, administrator of estate of James H. Utt, Fancy Gap; L. F. Webb, administrator of the estate of R. W. Vinson, Hillsville; J. T. Young, executor of estate of B. T. Young, Mecca; J. F. Blankenship, Sheriff, estates of William A. Allen, Fannie J. Ward, Sally Gentry, R. C. Quesinberry, William Marshall, and Charles M. Quesinberry; H. J. Smith, guardian of Joseph S. Smith and Mary A. Smith, Fancy Gap.
  - Folder 7. Correspondence - Carroll County. 1 May 1907 - 17 May 1907., 6 items. (Series-folder 2:7)
    This folder contains letters re: G. O. Banks, executor of estate of Isaac Banks, Snake Creek; David C. Frost, administrator of estate of Jane Dain, Pipers Gap; S. Eliza Burcham, guardian of her children, Pipers Gap; J. R. Lineberry, administrator, Monarat; and W. B. Cochran, administrator, Hillsville.
  - Folder 8. Correspondence - Pulaski County. 1901., 2 items. (Series-folder 2:8)
    This folder contains letters re: Mrs. M. A. Keszey, executors of M. A. Keszey estate, Radford Furnace; and Pharis Winns, guardian of Mary Scott, New River.
  - Folder 9. Correspondence - Pulaski County. 12 April 1906 - 13 April 1906., 7 items. (Series-folder 2:9)
    This folder contains letters re: R. C. Boothe, commissioner in C. B. Anderson et al vs. Newbern M. & M. Company et al, Newbern; Jennie P. Clark, administrator of estate of Winfree Clark, New River; Bird Duncan, administrator of estate of E. A. Leacher, Allisonia; E. M. Hawley, guardian of Hawley children, Radford; T. A. Windle, guardian of Ruby Windle and Windle children, Allisonia; H. M. Brown, East Radford; and K. E. Harman, executor, Pulaski.
  - Folder 10. Correspondence - Pulaski County. 14 April 1906 - 16 April 1906., 9 items. (Series-folder 2:10)
    This folder contains letters re: E. L. Bill, receiver for Snowville Mercantile Company, Snowville; A. L. Jordan and W. R. Jordan, guardian of Lizzie Painter and administrator of the estate of D. W. Jordan, Pulaski; Alice Smith, administrator of estate of Wilbur Smith, Pulaski; G. A. Calfree, administrator of estate of Ella M. Calfee, Pulaski; Lula S. Covey, guardian of her children, East Radford; J. W. Eckman, commissioner in Katherine L. Huffard vs. Gladys C. Huffard, Pulaski; E. C. Gannaway, guardian of Hurbert L. Friend and Gerberich children, Draper; F. W. Morton, attorney for J. C. Silcox who was blind and executor of estate of his wife E. J. Silcox, Pulaski; and Amanda Simpkins, administrator of estate of Thomas L. Simpkins, Snowville.
  - Folder 11. Correspondence - Pulaski County. 17 April 1906 - 20 April 1906., 4 items. (Series-folder 2:11)
    This folder contains letters re: D. C. Allison, administrator of estate, Roanoke; Mrs. Lilee B. Phelps, trustee, Pulaski; J. R. Clark, administrator of Ballard Clark, Delton; and Mrs. S. M. Baskerville, administrator of estate of S. M. Baskerville, Dublin.
  - Folder 12. Correspondence - Pulaski County. 23 April 1906 - 28 April 1906., 6 items. (Series-folder 2:12)
    This folder contains letters re: James B. Jordan, guardian of Anne Lee Jordan and Betty Jordan, Newbern; W. B. Morefield, administrator of estate of W. D. Faris, Newbern; W. C. Chaffin, administrator of the estate of Mary M. Painter, Pulaski; George M. Lucas, administrator of estate of W. R. Tipton, Roanoke, Virginia; J. M. Weiser, attorney for H. E. Harman, executor of estate of James B. Caddall, Dublin; and Matilda H. Combs, administrator of estate of Joseph Combs, Sassin.
  - Folder 13. Correspondence- Pulaski County. 1 May 1906 - 4 May 1906., 5 items. (Series-folder 2:13)
    This folder contains letters re: Allen T. Eskridge Jr., funds received by M. S. Tate as administrator of estate of Jane C. Tate, Pulaski; Henry C. Wysor, funds received by H. W. Wysor as executor of estate of S. W. Miller, Dublin; Gary Laughon, administrator of estate of [unknown] Johnson; Seldon Langley, commissioner in Charles O'Brian vs. Tobe Burks, East Radford; and Henry C. Wysor, administrator, Dublin.
  - Folder 14. Correspondence - Smyth County. 29 March 1906., 1 item. (Series-folder 2:14)
    This folder contains a letter re: Elva D. Robinson, guardian of E. Hetie Robinson, Marion.
  - Folder 15. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 25 May 1900, 6 June 1900., 2 items. (Series-folder 2:15)
    This folder contains letters re: E. King Crockett, executor of M. A. Smith estate and administrator of estate of Debra T. Crockett, Wittens Mill; and Chapman M. Peery, executor of estate of Auguste Le Conte and administrator of James Peery, and Mary L. Peery, guardian of Wade H. Peery, Paint Lick.
  - Folder 16. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 11 May 1903 - 12 May 1903., 7 items. (Series-folder 2:16)
    This folder contains letters re: J. W. Hicks, commissioner in Morton Harman et al vs. S. T. Litz and Morton Harman et al vs. Fleshman, Graham; P. M. Altizer, guardian of the Altizer children, Harman; W. M. Minter, administrator of Peter Sahoney, Pocahontas; George W. Oney, guardian of C. L. Lester and Dale Lester, Steelsburg; V. L. Sexton, administrator of Jack Bardsley, Pocahontas. and W. H. Worth, commissioner in Higginbotham et al vs. H. M. Smythe, Tazewell.
  - Folder 17. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 13 May 1903 - 14 May 1903., 5 items. (Series-folder 2:17)
    This folder contains letters re: A. P. Gillespie, receiver in cases of Perdue vs. Perdue's Administrator, J. S. Gillespie vs. J. W. Smith et als, Chapman vs. R. L. Gillespie, C. J. Hale vs. J. B. Greever et als, guardian of Lula Maude McGuire, Carrie E. McGuire, Marvin H. McGuire, John McGuire, and Sarah McGuire, Tazewell; J. W. Chapman, receiver in case M. E. Crockett vs. West Graham Land and Improvement Company, commissioner with H. C. Alderson in case Surface and wife vs. Groseclose et als, commissioner in G. W. Doak vs. Reese G. Harrison, commissioner with Greever and Hicks in Beasley vs. Thomas Peery et al, commissioner in Joseph A. McGuire vs. J. W. McGuire et al, receiver in Sue G. Hancock vs. J. G. Watts executor et al, Tazewell; R. C. Chapman, guardian of W. B. M. Chapman, Tazewell; G. W. Doak, guardian of R. E. Doak, Tazewell; and H. W. Pobst, administrator of Mrs. C. A. Nielle estate, Tazewell.
  - Folder 18. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 15 May 1903., 7 items. (Series-folder 2:18)
    This folder contains letters re: J. L. Brown, administrator of W. V. Brown estate, Tip Top; William Claytor, administrator of estate of S. O. Claytor, Thompson's Valley; T. C. George, administrator of estate of N. N. Holley, Tazewell; S. D. May, fiduciary in case Clark et al vs. Pillow, Heptinstall, Trustee vs. Cary et al, W. E. Thompson et al vs. T. B. Thompson, guardian of Alice May Marrs, Tazewell; W. M. Minter, re: funds received by Mrs. Nannie Franklin, adminstrator of estate of B. O. Franklin, Pocahontas; John W. Moore, administrator of estate of P. Bailey, Pocahontas; and J. w. Shannon, administrator of Jesse Bailey estate, Bailey.
  - Folder 19. Correspondence - Tazewell County - Bowen - Gillespie. 16 May 1903., 4 items. (Series-folder 2:19)
    This folder contains letters re: T. C. Bowen, receiver in case J. S. Browning and wife vs. Laurel Creek Coal and COke Company; Boxx Brown, receiver, Cedar Bluff; W. L. C. Burke, guardian, Big Creek; and R. S. Gillespie, executor of estate of W. P. Lang, Tazewell.
  - Folder 20. Correspondence - Tazewell County - Higginbotham - Weinberger. 16 May 1903., 5 items. (Series-folder 2:20)
    This folder contains letters re: A. Higginbotham, commissioner of the James Haskins estate, Tip Top; H. E. Hopkins, administrator of Dennis Honing estate, Tazewell; Mary L. Peery, guardian of W. H. Peery and Bessie V. Peery, Cedar Bluff; Chapman M. Peery, administrator of the L. E. Read and William Wilson estates, Paint Lick; V. L. Sexton, re: funds received by Thomas Tinsley as administrator of estate of G. B. Forster, Pocahontas; and Max Weinberger, administrator of estate of Steve Roszgony, Pocahontas.
  - Folder 21. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 18 May 1903., 8 items. (Series-folder 2:21)
    This folder contains letters re: Jno. H. Crockett for R. O. Crockett, administrator of Thomas Hall, Tazewell; J. W. Harman, administrator of Joel Sparks estate, Tazewell; George Harrison, guardian of Patrick heirs, Tazewell; R. R. Henry, commissioner in case of R. D. Brown vs. Stuart Crockett, Tazewell; G. P. McMullin, administrator of estate of F. S. Shawville, Springville; Isabelle A. Perkinson, committee for Mary Ann Holmes; C. C. Stowers, administrator, Stowersville; and P. H. Williams, administrator, Tazewell.
  - Folder 22. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 19 May 1903., 3 items. (Series-folder 2:22)
    This folder contains letters re: Chapman and Gillespie, re: funds received by J. O. Brown of Snapps as Administrator of O. M. Brown; Israel Nelson, receiver, Bear Wallow; and R. D. Young, administrator of Louise S. Young, Maxwell.
  - Folder 23. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 20 May 1903., 6 items. (Series-folder 2:23)
    This folder contains letter re: Walter A. Crowe, guardian of Samuel J. Crowe, Atlanta; Mrs. L. J. Lester, administrator, Wardell; R. H. McGraw, committee for Enaline Clyford, Steelburgh; James T. Moore, guardian, Bailey; R. W. Ratcliff, administrator of estate of Mary A. Ratcliff, Tazewell; and G. S. Thompson, guardian of his children, Benbow.
  - Folder 24. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 21 May 1903., 4 items. (Series-folder 2:24)
    This folder contains letters re: R. C. Chapman, guardian, Tazewell; Jno. W. Crockett for R. O. Crockett, administrator of Thomas Hall Estate, Tazewell; G. W. Doak, administrator of R. E. Doak estate and guardian of the Doak children, Tazewell; and Amanda Lester, administrator of estate of W. J. Lester, Steelsburg.
  - Folder 25. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 23 May 1903 - 25 May 1903., 8 items. (Series-folder 2:25)
    This folder contains letters re: Jno. W. Crockett, administrator of estate of Thomas Hall, Tazewell; J. F. Gillespie, administrator, Tazewell; George Sarver, guardian, Falls Mill; J. P. Clark, guardian, Swords Creek; L. E. Parter, guardian of Pearl Beavers,Graham; H. G. Peery, executor of estate of S. E. Peery, Tazewell; C. H. Steele, administrator of Andy Ascue estate, Paint Lick; and D. S. Tabor, guardian of children of E. B. Tabor, Pocahontas.
  - Folder 26. Correspondence - Tazewell County. 26 May - 29 May 1903., 9 items. (Series-folder 2:26)
    This folder contains letters re: Joseph H. Beavers, guardian of Rachel Brewster, Baptist Valley; M. F> Brown, receiver, Tannersville; Joseph McMullin administrator of estate of G. P. McMullin, Springville; William Claytor, administrator of estate of S. O. Claytor, Tazewell; J. Marion McGuire, receiver, Cedar Bluff; G. S. Thompson, guardian, Benbow; Susan Beavers, administrator of estate of A. J. Beavers, Bandy; S. S. Gregory, administrator, Shawver Mill; and L. F. Lester, guardian, Wardell.
  - Correspondence - Tazewell County. June 1903, 13 June 1907., 4 items. (Series-folder 2:27)
    This folder contains letters re: W. H. Flood, administrator of estate of John T. Redd; L. C. Long, administrator of estate of E. P. Long, Gray; E. King Crockett, administrator of estate of M. A. Smith, Wittens Mill; and C. M. Galway, of Bank of Pocahontas.
  - Folder 28. Correspondence - Wythe County. 1901, 1 February 1906., 3 items. (Series-folder 2:28)
    This folder contains letters and statements re: W. T. Graham, administrator of estate of David P. Graham and Nannie Tate Montgomery Graham as guardian, Graham's Forge; S. R. Crockett, administrator; and G. W. Sharitz, administrator of the estate of John P. Sharitz.
  - Folder 29. Correspondence - Wythe County. 28 March - 29 March 1906., 5 items. (Series-folder 2:29)
    This folder contains letters re: C. C. Catron, guardian of Lolie E. Jones, Rural Retreat; E. M> Davis, executor of estate of William Davis, Rural Retreat; M. M. Caldwell, receiver; Waller S. Poage, funds received by Stuart R. Umberger as administrator of estate of Joseph S. Umberger; and Polly Weaver, administrator, Rural Retreat.
  - Folder 30. Correspondence - Wythe County. 30 March 1906., 7 items. (Series-folder 2:30)
    This folder contains letters re: Daniel Coalson, guardian, Foster Falls; J. H. Coley, administrator of estate of Margaret Coley, Rural Retreat; Robert Enoch Withers, guardian of Edna Copenhaver, Wytheville; George M. Lucas, guardian of Sarah H. Lucas and Elsie L. Lucas, Roanoke; H. J. Mathew, receiver in case of W. P. Kent vs. Anastasia Kent et al, Max Meadows; Sallie S. Musser, commissioner in case of Nannie Huddle vs. Musser administrator et al, Rural Retreat; and W. S. Thorn, guardian for Eugene G. Thorn, Austinville.
- Series III. Literary Drafts - Word Sketches. Undated., 9 folders
  This series contains handwritten drafts by Mary Cloyd Kent Withers of her book Word Sketches of Some of her Relatives. Also included are research notes on the Kent family, Byars family, Cloyd family, Craig family, Crockett family, and Montgomery family.
- Series IV. Books. 1881, Undated., 2 folders.
  This series contains a ledger listing Virginia localities and post offices and Myers Tactics: the Templar Manual by E. B. Myers, published in 1881.
- Series V. Photographs. Undated., 1 folder.
  This series contains a folder with five photographs including Robert Edwin Withers Sr., Robert Edwin Withers Jr., Robert Edwin Withers Sr. in an automobile, Robert Edwin Withers Sr. and Robert Edwin Withers Jr. in automobile, and a family group in Hong Kong.
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Records. 1938-1942., 2 folders.
  - Folder 1. Miscellaneous Records - Aluminum Company of America. 1938, 1942, 5 items. (Series-folder 6:1)
    This folder contains the following relating to the Aluminum Company of America: program, In Celebration of the Fiftieth Birthday of the Aluminum Industry, 1938, Fiftieth Birthday of the Aluminum Industry: Seating Arrangement, 1938; program, Presentation of Navy E to New Kensington Works of Aluminum Company of America at New Kensington, Pa., April 14, 1942; Schedule of Events and Platform Seating Diagram for Navy E Award Ceremony, 1942; and memo to Robert Edwin Withers Sr. regarding the New Kensington Navy E Ceremony, 1942.
  - Folder 2. Miscellaneous Records - Virginia Military Institute. 1939., 5 items. (Series-folder 6:2)
    This folder contains the following relating to the centennial celebration of Virginia Military Institute 10 June 1939 to 14 June 1939: Program of Exercises; invitation card to reception at Superintendent's house; invitation to hops or dances; reserved parking space ticket; and medal R. E. Withers, class of 1885, V. M. I. Centennial, 1839-1939.